<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>computational social sciences | MilaNLP Lab @ Bocconi University</title>
    <link>https://milanlproc.github.io/tags/computational-social-sciences/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://milanlproc.github.io/tags/computational-social-sciences/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>computational social sciences</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© MilaNLP, 2023</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>computational social sciences</title>
      <link>https://milanlproc.github.io/tags/computational-social-sciences/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Postdoctoral Researcher - Natural Language Processing</title>
      <link>https://milanlproc.github.io/open_positions/postdoc_position_nlp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://milanlproc.github.io/open_positions/postdoc_position_nlp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PI: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://milanlproc.github.io/authors/2_debora_nozza/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Debora Nozza&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are seeking a highly motivated and talented individual to join our research team as a Postdoctoral Researcher in the field of Natural Language Processing. The position offers an exciting opportunity to investigate the computational and algorithmic aspects underlying modern Artificial Intelligence systems, with a specific focus on the algorithmic and application aspects of NLP-based technologies. Successful candidates will work closely with Prof. Debora Nozza, Prof. Dirk Hovy, and the MilaNLP lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your profile:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a Ph.D. in Computer Science, Computational Linguistics/NLP, Machine Learning, Data Science, or related fields.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excellent programming skills in Python. Additional languages (C++, R, etc) a plus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fluency in spoken and written English. Knowledge of Italian is NOT a requirement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knowledge of current neural network models and implementation tools for neural networks (e.g. PyTorch).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience with publications in top-tier venues in the field of NLP/Computational Linguistics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Position Details:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Starting date: Oct 1 2023, or any time thereafter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Duration: 2 years&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deadline: 1st September 2023&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Competitive Salary: Applicants from outside Italy may qualify for a researcher taxation scheme&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Date posted: 12th July 2023&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to apply:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go to the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://jobmarket.unibocconi.eu/?type=a&amp;amp;urlBack=/wps/wcm/connect/Bocconi/SitoPubblico_IT/Albero&amp;#43;di&amp;#43;navigazione/Home/docenti&amp;#43;e&amp;#43;ricerca/docenti/Reclutamento&amp;#43;docenti/Concorsi/Assegni&amp;#43;di&amp;#43;Ricerca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Bocconi postdoc job market page&lt;/a&gt; and search for &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Natural language processing&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo;.
Official job description at this 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://jobmarket.unibocconi.eu/include/dwload.php?a=NjUxXjgyNTgxYjQyOGEyOTE3OWY5MzNmNTZhZDIwODUyNjkxXnVwbG9hZC9EUkIvc2Vzc2lvbl8zOTItMjAyMzA3MTJeam1rX3Nlc19maWxlXmptZl9eam1mX2ZpbGVeMTcwNQ==&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;. Candidates should attach publications and a cover letter to their application. Online interviews will take place during September 2023. Please contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:debora.nozza@unibocconi.it&#34;&gt;debora.nozza@unibocconi.it&lt;/a&gt; if you have any question.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MONICA</title>
      <link>https://milanlproc.github.io/project/monitoring_italian_measures_response_covid19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://milanlproc.github.io/project/monitoring_italian_measures_response_covid19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PI: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://milanlproc.github.io/authors/debora_nozza/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Debora Nozza&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;co-PI: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://milanlproc.github.io/authors/1_dirk_hovy/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dirk Hovy&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://didattica.unibocconi.eu/docenti/cv.php?rif=92152&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nicoletta Balbo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interdisciplinary MONICA project will create a &lt;strong&gt;digital barometer of Italians’ attitudes towards the government measures implemented in response to COVID-19&lt;/strong&gt;. The pandemic has plunged millions of vulnerable people into abject poverty. The government created financial measures to improve the economic situation and social inclusion. However, it is unclear whether these measures reach those who need them most.
To find out, we will uncover the public perception of these measures and provide concrete metrics for three related dimensions: 1) coverage of the potential beneficiaries, 2) attitudes of the Italian population stratified by different demographic factors, and 3) accessibility of the information. MONICA will provide citizens with a tool to automatically rank and simplify articles about requirements and steps to access these initiatives. MONICA will enable policymakers to understand which segments of the vulnerable population are not accessing these initiatives and why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See this project featured in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.knowledge.unibocconi.eu/notizia.php?idArt=23183&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;news&lt;/a&gt;. 🗞️🗞️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🇮🇹 &lt;em&gt;Italian version&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Per fronteggiare le ripercussioni economiche della pandemia, il governo italiano ha adottato diverse misure finanziarie volte ad arginare gli effetti della crisi, migliorando l’inclusione sociale delle persone che negli ultimi mesi si sono trovate in difficoltà. Tuttavia, tali misure hanno inaspettatamente riscosso una partecipazione inferiore alle aspettative e la loro efficacia, soprattutto in termini di raggiungimento dei soggetti più bisognosi, risulta difficilmente verificabile.
MONICA, analizzando una grande mole di dati tramite tecniche di data science, fornirà delle metriche atte a valutare tali misure in termini di: 1) capacità di raggiungimento dei soggetti bisognosi, 2) sentiment dell’opinione pubblica, differenziata in base a fattori demografici, 3) accessibilità delle informazioni. MONICA, inoltre, automaticamente cercherà e creerà versioni semplificate di articoli e procedure inerenti alle misure, garantendo l’accessibilità di tali informazioni a tutti i cittadini.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
