<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>media | MilaNLP Lab @ Bocconi University</title>
    <link>https://milanlproc.github.io/tags/media/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://milanlproc.github.io/tags/media/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>media</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© MilaNLP, 2024</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>media</title>
      <link>https://milanlproc.github.io/tags/media/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Postdoctoral Researcher - Computational Social Science/NLP</title>
      <link>https://milanlproc.github.io/open_positions/postdoc_position_compsocsci/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://milanlproc.github.io/open_positions/postdoc_position_compsocsci/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PI: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://kaizhu.me/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Kai Zhu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;computational-social-science-with-a-focus-on-natural-language-processing-and-societal-impact-of-media-ecosystem&#34;&gt;Computational Social Science with a Focus on Natural Language Processing and Societal Impact of Media Ecosystem&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are happy to announce a Postdoctoral position at Bocconi University in computational social science, emphasizing natural language processing (NLP) and societal impact of the media ecosystem. This position is a unique opportunity to work on projects that explore the interplay between social media and mass media in shaping public narratives and collective attention. The successful candidate will work closely with 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://kaizhu.me/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Prof. Kai Zhu&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://milanlproc.github.io/authors/1_dirk_hovy/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Prof. Dirk Hovy&lt;/a&gt;, and will have the opportunity to be part of the MilaNLP Lab and BIDSA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Project Overview:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Title: Exploring Societal Impact of Media Ecosystem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Application Deadline: 2024-01-31&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Starting Date: 2024-03-01 or anytime thereafter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Duration: 21 months&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Total compensation: 87,500 Euro&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Research Focus: Investigating the dynamic relationship between social media discussions, mass media coverage, and collective attention/public attitude toward social issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unique Dataset: The candidate will have the opportunity to work on large-scale data capturing text transcripts from more than 800 national and local television channels across all 210 Designated Market Areas (DMAs) in the United States, spanning from January 2013 to August 2022. This dataset includes over 10 million hours of television broadcasting and over 60 billion words, covering news, sports, entertainment, commercials, and educational content. It uniquely includes content from local channels tailored to specific regional interests and concerns.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key Responsibilities:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Process and analyze the large-scale TV content transcript dataset, focusing on extracting meaningful insights relevant to social issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collaborate with a multidisciplinary team and contribute to the development of innovative models to understand the role of media in shaping social issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The candidate is encouraged to create new projects based on the available dataset and demonstrate innovation and independence in their academic research. This includes formulating original research questions, developing novel methodologies, and contributing unique insights to the field.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key Qualifications:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience with Large-Scale Text Data: Demonstrated experience in handling and analyzing large-scale text datasets, including data preprocessing and text mining.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expertise in NLP: Solid training in NLP, including experience with modern techniques and models.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interest in Computational Social Science: Keen interest in applying NLP to social science questions, particularly in analyzing the interplay between social and mass media in shaping social issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Application Process:
Interested candidates should submit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a detailed CV,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a cover letter outlining research interests and career goals,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a paper sample of your choice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To submit your application, please go to the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://jobmarket.unibocconi.eu/?type=a&amp;amp;urlBack=/wps/wcm/connect/Bocconi/SitoPubblico_IT/Albero&amp;#43;di&amp;#43;navigazione/Home/docenti&amp;#43;e&amp;#43;ricerca/docenti/Reclutamento&amp;#43;docenti/Concorsi/Assegni&amp;#43;di&amp;#43;Ricerca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Bocconi postdoc job market page&lt;/a&gt;) and search for &lt;strong&gt;“EXPLORING SOCIETAL IMPACT OF MEDIA ECOSYSTEM”&lt;/strong&gt;.
For any questions, please email Kai Zhu at 
&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:kai.zhu@unibocconi.it&#34;&gt;kai.zhu@unibocconi.it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
