<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>computational social science | MilaNLP Lab @ Bocconi University</title>
    <link>https://milanlproc.github.io/tags/computational-social-science/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://milanlproc.github.io/tags/computational-social-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>computational social science</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© MilaNLP, 2023</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>computational social science</title>
      <link>https://milanlproc.github.io/tags/computational-social-science/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Postdoctoral Researcher - Computational Social Science</title>
      <link>https://milanlproc.github.io/open_positions/postdoc_position_compsocsci/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://milanlproc.github.io/open_positions/postdoc_position_compsocsci/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PI: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://carloschwarz.eu&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Carlo Schwarz&lt;/a&gt;
co-PI 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://milanlproc.github.io/authors/1_dirk_hovy/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dirk Hovy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last decade, discontent in democracy, mistrust in institutions, and the rise of populist parties have strained European societies. Underlying these tensions are often increasing inequalities in Western countries, which fuel the discontent of individuals. The Covid pandemic further exacerbated these problems, as anti-Covid measures taken by governments differently impacted societal groups. The MENTALISM project combines modern social media analysis with traditional survey data to track inequality across Italy through the lens of the pandemic.
Our ground-breaking mixed-methods approach uses machine learning and text analysis to trace online grievances in a vast corpus of social media data. We combine these methods with survey protocols and econometric analysis to validate the findings and provide actionable policy advice. MENTALISM combines the advantages of social media data (high-frequency, individual-level information) with the strength of socio-economic surveys (representativeness). Our novel interdisciplinary approach will critically evaluate the value of social media monitoring for policy feedback. Moreover, it will establish protocols for policymakers to better respond to growing grievances brought on by inequality at various steps in the process.
Successful candidates will work closely with Profs. Carlo Schwarz (economics), Dirk Hovy (NLP), and the MilaNLP lab.
Your profile:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a Ph.D. in Computer Science, Computational Linguistics/NLP, Machine Learning, Data Science, or related fields.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excellent programming skills in Python. Additional languages (C++, R, etc) a plus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fluency in spoken and written English. Knowledge of Italian is NOT a requirement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knowledge of current neural network models and implementation tools for neural networks (e.g. PyTorch, Tensorflow, Keras, etc.).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience with publications in top-tier venues in the field of NLP/Computational Linguistics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Position Details:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Starting date: March 1 2023, or any time thereafter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Duration: 1 year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deadline: 18th February 2023&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Salary: 42k EUR p.a. (median salary Milan: 37k EUR). Applicants from outside Italy may qualify for a researcher taxation scheme&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Date posted: 18th January 2023&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to apply:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go to the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://jobmarket.unibocconi.eu/?type=a&amp;amp;urlBack=/wps/wcm/connect/bocconi/sitopubblico_it/albero&amp;#43;di&amp;#43;navigazione/home/docenti&amp;#43;e&amp;#43;ricerca/docenti/reclutamento&amp;#43;docenti/concorsi/assegni&amp;#43;di&amp;#43;ricerca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Bocconi postdoc job market page&lt;/a&gt; and search for &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;BAFFI CAREFIN&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;. There are two positions, in13/A1 ECONOMICS and 01/B1 INFORMATICS.
You will then have to click on &amp;ldquo;Apply online&amp;rdquo; for proceeding with the application. See below the screenshot of the application platform.
Official job description at this 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://jobmarket.unibocconi.eu/include/dwload.php?a=MzQxXjE1YzQzZDE3NTVmOTdjZTc2ZmUzZDRhYzJiYTMzOWFmXi9kMC9hcGFjaGUvam9ibWFya2V0LnVuaWJvY2NvbmkuZXUvZGF0YS91cGxvYWQvQkFGL3Nlc3Npb25fMjkyLTIwMjMwMTE4Xmpta19zZXNfZmlsZV5qbWZfXmptZl9maWxlXjExMTI=&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;.
Candidates should attach publications and a cover letter to their application.
Online interviews will presumably take place during March 2023.
Please contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:dirk.hovy@unibocconi.it&#34;&gt;dirk.hovy@unibocconi.it&lt;/a&gt; if you have any questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;how_to_apply.png&#34; alt=&#34;How to apply&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MiMac</title>
      <link>https://milanlproc.github.io/project/mimac/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://milanlproc.github.io/project/mimac/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this inter-disciplinary project, Dirk Hovy and Tommaso Fornaciari team up with an international team of political scientists (led bt the University of Gothenburg) to develop mixed methods for analyzing political parties’ promises to voters during election campaigns. For democracy to function effectively, political parties must offer clear choices to voters during election campaigns. However, as parties’ communication with voters has become increasingly fragmented and targeted, it is much harder for citizens to keep track of what parties are promising. This threatens the quality of democratic representation. It also challenges established research methods for studying parties’ campaign promises. This project will develop new methods for studying parties’ promises in modern election campaigns. The project will integrate existing qualitative methods in political science and develop new research tools based on NLP. These AI-powered tools will enable researchers to examine parties’ campaign promises in large amounts of text and speech. The resulting research will be of significant benefit to citizens, who will receive greater clarity on the choices that parties are offering. These existing and new methods are highly relevant to research on text and speech in a wide range of social science fields. Until now, progress in this field has been stifled by limited dialogue among the proponents of different qualitative and quantitative methods. The project includes established experts on parties’ campaign promises, new media, qualitative and quantitative methods for analyzing political texts, and machine learning and natural language processing.
The project is funded by the Swedish 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rj.se/en/anslag/2019/mixed-methods-for-analyzing-political-parties-promises-to-voters-during-election-campaigns/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Riksbankens Jubileumsfond&lt;/a&gt; for 12M SEK.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
